

CONTACT



Grote Kromme Elleboog 1c,, Groningen, NL 9712 BJ



0627499566



r.e.kaundinya@rug.nl



https://rkaundinya.github.io/

SKILLS

- C, C++, C#, Go, Python, ACT-R, Java, Javascript, MATLAB; SQL, PyTorch, Numpy, Tensorflow, Qiskit, Nengo
- Unity and Unreal Game Engines
- VR and Game Development
- Reinforcement Learning, Multi-Layer Neural Networks, Deep Learning, Cognitive Architectures, NLP, Cloud Computing, High Performance Computing, Quantum Computing
- Cognitive Science background

LANGUAGES

English

Native

Telugu

Intermediate

Spanish

Intermediate

Ram Eshwar Kaundinya

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

PhD Candidate researching biologically plausible Artificial Intelligence. Gameplay Engineer working with veteran game developers from Civilization, XCom, The Sims, and Skyrim. Researching neuromorphic chips, cognitive architectures, memristors, and cognitive models. Working towards energy efficient computing. Strong professional software engineering background and academically trained in cognitive science and Al. A lifelong musician and curious human being!

WORK HISTORY

Software Engineer

03/2024 - Present

Midsummer Studios - Hunt Valley, Maryland

- Al and Gameplay programming
- Telemetry system programming
- Maintaining and updating internal documentation
- Large Language Model and cloud services integration

Engineer

03/2022 - 03/2024

Firaxis Games - Sparks, Maryland

- Shipped game partnered with Marvel Studios called Marvel's Midnight Suns
- Live services, multiplayer, and analytics programming in collaboration with 2K Analytics
- Gameplay engineering on Civilization 7
- Programmed AI decision making and abilities for Marvel's Midnight Suns
- Shipped and maintained the mission system for Marvel's Midnight Suns

EDUCATION

PhD: University of Groningen, 09/2024 - Present

Working on sensorimotor applications using tactile data and neuromoprhic algorithms.. Recent paper on an adaptive controller using biologically plausible spiking neural network encodings. Researching the intersection of dynamical systems, control theory, and cognition.. Working with Cognigron and the NL-ECO Consortium on energy efficient computing.

Master of Science: Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning, 03/2022 - 03/2024

Drexel University - Philadelphia

Studies included reinforcement learning, high performance computing, cloud native engineering, cognitive architectures, machine learning, deep learning, quantum computing, and more.

Bachelor of Science : Cognitive Science, 09/2015 - 06/2019 **University of California Los Angeles** - Los Angeles

Worked with Professor Uri Maoz on decision making research and Professor Patricia Cheng on principles of perception. Studies included research design, psychology, digital humanities, and computing.